Pedro Revilla

Software Engineer.

I am an Electronic Engineer with 6 years' experience in IT infrastructure. I switched my career path to software Engineering. I have experience building web applications client and server side. Knowledge in CS data Structures and Algorithms.

Website: https://www.pedro-revilla.com/github.com/peterevilla
Chicago, IL

(312)-929-7879 peterevilla@gmail.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

AWT World Trade, Chicago, IL — IT Support Specialist

June 2017 - PRESENT

- Responsible for the architecture, implementation, evolution, operation and maintenance of enterprise IT infrastructure systems in a manufacturing environment linked to an ERP system.
- Active Directory, DNS, and DHCP configuration and troubleshooting.
- Company Website maintenance Frontend/Backend. HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, SQL.
- Perform PowerShell scripts to automate daily tasks.
- Develop new strategies and IT procedures to increase efficiency, enhance workflow, and improve customer satisfaction.
- Implementation and deployment of a backup solution with AWS EC2 and S3.
- Batch scripting to write security policies in GPO.

CANTV, Venezuela — *Backup Engineer*

May 2011 - June 2016

- Worked with NetBackup 6.5 7.5 and over in a large environment on both Unix and Windows Servers.
- Performed installation, configuration, upgrading, patching and troubleshooting on Master, Media and clients servers.
- Responsible for troubleshooting daily backups issues (Over 500 clients).
- Involved in 24/7 on-call support rotation with 3 other third level support coworkers
- Participated in disaster recovery/system recovery exercises.
- Setup of policy attributes in a best way multiplexing, multi-streaming and diskstaging to perform faster backups and restoration.
- Worked with Storage Tek 4500 (10,000 tapes) and Spectra Logic (3,000 tapes) automated tape libraries.
- Responsibility over storage units and volume pools.

SKILLS

Programming Languages

JavaScript (ES6), Typescript, Python.

Libraries, Frameworks & State Mgmt.

React, Node.js, Express, Redux, Context API, Tailwindcss.

Database

PostgreSQL, SQLite, KnexJs, TypeORM

Testing Libraries

Jest, Supertest

Tools & Platforms

Git, Github, Heroku, Vercel, Netlify, AWS, Jira, Figma.

EDUCATION

Lambda School 2019-present// USA Computer Software Engineering.

Lambda School is a 9+ month computer science & software engineering program that provides an immersive hands-on curriculum with a focus on computer science, and full stack web development

UNEXPO 2004-2010// Venezuela

Bachelor of Engineering degree in electronics.

LANGUAGES AND INTERESTS

Bilingual (Spanish-English) - Music.